A Finding Aid to the Beatrice Fenton Papers, 1836-1984, bulk 1890-1978, in the Archives of American Art AAA.fentbeat
Archives of American Art
Beatrice Fenton papers
bulk 1890-1978
1836-1984
AAA.fentbeat
Archives of American Art
9.3 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor Beatrice Fenton date from 1836-1984 (bulk 1890-1978) and measure 9.3 linear feet. The collection documents Fenton's career as a sculptor and art instructor, as well as her life-long friendships with artist Emily Clayton and art educator Marjorie Martinet. Found are scattered biographical materials, correspondence primarily with Martinet (approximately 1/2 of the collection), business records, notes and writings, scattered records of arts organizations, transcripts of interviews with Fenton, sketches and sketchbooks, a scrapbook, brochures, clippings, postcards, reproductions of artwork, and photographs of friends and family, travels, and artwork. Writings include several illustrated hand-made books of poetry by Emily Clayton.
Beatrice Fenton
Provenance
The Beatrice Fenton papers were donated from 1987-1991 by Joan Martin, a sculptor and former Fenton student, who inherited Fenton's studio and its contents.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Biographical Note
Beatrice Fenton was born on July 12, 1887 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to ophthalmologist Thomas H. Fenton and Lizzie Remak Fenton, who was the daughter of prominent lawyer Gustavus Remak.
From 1903-1904 Fenton began to study art at the Philadelphia School of Industrial Art under Alexander Stirling Calder. Through her father's aunt, Mary Fenton Holmes, she met Thomas Eakins who advised her to sculpt in clay in order to overcome flatness in drawings. In 1904 Eakins painted a portrait of Fenton as the central figure in The Coral Necklace.
Fenton was attracted to sculpture and continued her studies in this field from 1904-1908 at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts in Philadelphia, under Charles Grafly. Here she began life-long friendships with fellow students Marjorie Martinet and Emily Clayton Bishop.
A Cresson European Traveling Scholarship enabled Fenton to visit Belgium, Germany, Austria, Switzerland, Italy, Greece, France, and England during the summer of 1909. She returned to the Pennsylvania Academy and won a second scholarship that financed further travel to Spain, France, Holland, Belgium, and England in 1910 with Marjorie Martinet. On her return from Europe Fenton began working as an artist in Philadelphia.
Both Fenton and Martinet were deeply affected by the sudden death of Emily Clayton Bishop in 1912, and spent several years promoting Bishop's sculpture. Martinet, who changed the spelling of her surname from Martenet to Martinet in June 1918, established her own art school in Baltimore, Maryland, and later taught painting at the Maryland Institute of Art. Fenton and Martinet maintained a close relationship for fifty years, primarily through correspondence.
Fenton's first success came with a portrait bust of her father's friend, painter and etcher Peter Moran, brother of Thomas Moran. The bust was purchased by the painter's friends for the Art Club and in 1915 won Honorable Mention in the Panama-Pacific International Exposition in San Francisco. The success of Fenton's Seaweed Fountain in 1922 generated many commissions, primarily for fountains.
Martinet taught at Oldfields School from 1925 to 1961. From 1942 to 1953, Fenton taught at the Moore College of Art in Philadelphia, and later joined the faculty of St. John's Night School for Adults.
Beatrice Fenton died February 11, 1983 in Germantown, Pennsylvania.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of sculptor Beatrice Fenton date from 1836-1984 (bulk 1890-1978) and measure 9.3 linear feet. The collection documents Fenton's career as a sculptor and art instructor, as well as her life-long friendships with artist Emily Clayton and art educator Marjorie Martinet. Found are scattered biographical materials, correspondence primarily between Fenton and Martinet (approximately 1/2 of the collection), business records, notes and writings, scattered records of arts organizations, transcripts of interviews with Fenton, sketches and sketchbooks, a scrapbook, brochures, clippings, postcards, reproductions of artwork, and photographs of friends and family, travels, and artwork.
The collection includes scattered biographical material for Fenton, Emily Clayton Bishop, and Marjorie Martinet, such as biographical accounts, membership cards, and a diploma. The correspondence is primarily between Fenton and Martinet and documents the development of their close friendship and professional concerns. There are also scattered letters from Fenton's instructor, Alexander S. Calder and Emily Clayton Bishop. Personal business records include those of Fenton and Martinet and include wills, estate papers, insurance and banking records, price lists, receipts, and records from the Oldfields School where Marjorie Martinet taught for 36 years. Found within the Notes and Writings series are address books, hand-made illustrated booklets of poems by Emily Clayton Bishop, lecture manuscripts, and notes and typescripts on various topics, including a file Fenton created to promote Bishop's artwork following Bishop's death.
There is a series of scattered records of arts organizations to which Fenton belonged, including the Charcoal Club, the Three Arts Club, Lizette Wood Reese Memorial Association, and the Maryland Institute Alumni Association. Also found in the papers are interview tapes and transcripts of interviews conducted with Fenton by Mary Hamel-Schwulst and Marlene Obarzaneck, artwork consisting primarily of sketchbooks and loose drawings by Fenton and Bishop, a scrapbook concerning Martinet, additional printed material, and photographs and photograph albums depicting Fenton, Martinet, Bishop, other family, colleagues, studios, artwork, and travel destinations.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1897-1967 (Boxes 1, 10; 5 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1857-1980 (Boxes 1-5, 10; 4.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, 1836, 1907-1978 (Box 5; 39 folders)
Series 4: Notes and Writings, 1866-1971 (Boxes 5-6; 58 folders)
Series 5: Organization Records, 1903-1938 (Box 6; 9 folders)
Series 6: Interviews, 1978 (Box 6; 5 folders)
Series 7: Artwork, 1903-1943 (Boxes 7, 10; 21 folders)
Series 8: Scrapbook, 1905-1925 (Boxes 10; 1 folder)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1865-1984 (Boxes 7-8, 10; 1.7 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1890-1978 (Boxes 9-10, MGP 6; 1.0 linear feet)
Bishop, Emily Clayton, 1883-1912; Martinet, Marjorie D., 1886-1981; Interviews; Photographs; Sculptors--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Sound recordings; Women sculptors--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia
- Biographical Material, 1897-1967; Series 1; 5 Folders Boxes 1, 10
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material for Fenton includes biographical accounts and student passes. There is also a Catholic confirmation card and a card of membership in the International Order of the King's Daughters and Sons for Emily Clayton Bishop, and a curriculum vita, diploma, and membership cards for Marjorie Martinet.
  - Student Passes for Fenton, 1904-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Accounts for Fenton, 1926-1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Material for Emily Clayton Bishop, 1897-1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Material for Marjorie Martinet, 1904-1967; (see also Box 10) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diploma from the Maryland Institute for Marjorie Martinet, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1857-1980; Series 2; 4.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-5, 10
  Correspondence consists primarily of an intimate decades-long exchange of letters between Fenton and Martinet. There are also scattered letters from Fenton's instructor, Alexander S. Calder, and Emily Clayton Bishop, as well as scattered letters addressed to Martinet from others, including a cover letter from William Merritt Chase for a letter of recommendation written on Martinet's behalf. The bulk of the correspondence is arranged Most of the undated letters are filed alphabetically before the chronological correspondence. Undated letters from Fenton and Martinet have been filed separately from other undated correspondence, also before the chronological correspondence.
  - Unidentified Correspondents, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondents with Surnames A-B, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondents with Surnames C-F, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Beatrice Fenton, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondents with Surnames G-L, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Marjorie Martinet, undated (Box 1, Folder 10-15)
  - Correspondents with Surnames N-Z, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1857-1868 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1870-1877 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1887-1896 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1900-1909 (Box 1, Folder 20-26)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 27-34)
    See also Box 10.
  - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 35-41)
  - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 42-61)
  - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 62-75)
  - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 76-83)
  - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 8-25)
  - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 26-41)
  - Correspondence, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 43-51)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 52-55)
  - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 56-64)
  - Correspondence, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 65-70)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 71-72)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 11-32)
  - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 33-47)
  - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 48-56)
  - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 57-60)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 61-66)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 67-69)
  - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 70-73)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 75-78)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 79-80)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1937 (Box 4, Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 9-16)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 4, Folder 19-26)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 27-32)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 33-37)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 38-40)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 41-43)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 44-47)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 48-53)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 54-59)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 60-63)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 64-67)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 68-70)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4-10)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 11-16)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17-22)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 23-27)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1980 (Box 5, Folder 28-32)
  - Oversized Letter from Emily Clayton Bishop to Fenton, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Business Records, 1836, 1907-1978; Series 3; 39 Folders Box 5
  Business records consist of legal documents including indenture papers, wills, estate papers, and insurance records for various Fenton family members, as well as miscellaneous financial records including banking records, price lists, and records from the Oldfields School where Marjorie Martinet taught for 36 years.
  Arrangement note
  Estate records, indenture papers and wills are followed by other business records arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Estate Papers for Fenton, Hector T., 1933-1944 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Estate Papers for Fenton, Lizzie Remak, 1920-1926 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Estate Papers, Will, for Bidlack, Laura V. (Fenton's paternal aunt), 1926-1932 (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
  - Estate Papers, Will, for Fenton, Thomas H., 1925-1929 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Estate Papers, Will, for Sheppard, Laura (Fenton's cousin), 1935-1947 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Indenture Papers for Martenet, Charles Frederick, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Will of Fenton, Beatrice, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Will of Martinet, Marjorie D., 1955 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Banking Records, 1919-1978 (Box 5, Folder 42-45)
  - Financial Records, Miscellaneous Art-Related, 1907-1960 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Income Tax Returns, 1937-1963 (Box 5, Folder 47-49)
  - Insurance Records, 1946-1964 (Box 5, Folder 50-52)
  - Leases and Records of Rent Payments, 1908-1924 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Notebook of European Travel Expenses, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Notebook of Household Expenses and Writings in German, 1944-1947 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Oldfields School Financial Records, 1930-1960 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Price Lists for Artwork, 1911-1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 57-58)
  - Promissory Notes, 1927-1934 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Real Estate Records, 1937-1968 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Receipts for Casting and Carving of Artwork, 1912-1951 (Box 5, Folder 61-67)
  - Receipts for Household Expenses, 1922-1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Receipts, Miscellaneous, 1923-1974 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Receipts, Miscellaneous Travel, 1909-1964 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Stocks and Bonds Records, 1950-1973 (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Notes and Writings, 1866-1971; Series 4; 58 Folders Boxes 5-6
  This series includes address books, art class notebooks and a journal from a trip to Greece, as well as notes concerning Fenton's friend Emily Clayton Bishop, and Marjorie Martinet's ancestors, the Hood family. Also included are Bishop's illustrated hand-made books of poetry, lecture typescripts, and miscellaneous writings.
  - Address Book 1, Fenton, undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Address Book 2, Fenton, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Address Book, Marjorie Martinet, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Addresses, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Anatomy Notebook, Fenton, 1905-1906 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Card File of Artwork, 1912-1963 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
  - Class Lists, 1942-1962, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Illustrated Booklet, Some Sonnets by Sir Philip Sidney, Illustrated by Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Illustrated Booklet of Poems, Spring, by Emily Clayton Bishop, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Illustrated Booklet of Poems, Versicles, by Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Itinerary for Travel to the American West, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript for Daughters of Troy, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Manuscript for Lecture at the Progress Club, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript for Lecture on Sculpture, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Notes Concerning Emily Clayton Bishop, 1912-1920 (Box 6, Folder 17-25)
  - Notes Concerning the Hood Family, 1866-1944, undated (Box 6, Folder 26-31)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1915-1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 32-35)
  - Poem, Escarda, by Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Travel Journal for Greece, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Typescript for A Persian Cat by Marjorie Martinet, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Typescript for Lecture, American Women Artists of Today, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Writings, Miscellaneous, 1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 40-44)
  - Writings, Poems, undated (Box 6, Folder 45-46)
- Organization Records, 1903-1938; Series 5; 9 Folders Box 6
  This series contains records of the Charcoal Club, the Lizette Wood Reese Memorial Association for which Fenton designed a bas-relief memorial tablet, the Maryland Institute Alumni Association, and the Three Arts Club. Records include notes, by-laws, minutes and typescripts.
  - Charcoal Club, Constitution, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Lizette Wood Reese Memorial Association (Box 6)
    - Membership Lists, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Minutes of Meetings, 1938-1938 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Typescripts, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Maryland Institute Alumni Association (Box 6)
    - Bulletins, 1903-1915 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1903-1913 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Three Arts Club (Box 6)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Minutes of Meetings, 1907-1910 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1912-1913, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Interviews, 1978; Series 6; 5 Folders Box 6
  This series consists of audio cassettes and transcripts of interviews with Fenton conducted by Dr. Mary Hamel-Schwulst and Marlene Obarzaneck. There is also an audio cassette of a television program, "From the Lands of Scythians," narrated by Thams Hering.
  - Audio Cassettes of Interviews of Fenton, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 56-58)
  - Transcripts of Interviews of Fenton, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 59-60)
  - Audio Cassette of Television Program, undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Artwork, 1903-1943; Series 7; 21 Folders Boxes 7, 10
  Artwork consists of sketchbooks, loose sketches, and an engraved portrait of Thomas H. Fenton. Because Fenton, combined the unsigned work of her colleagues with her own, correct attributions of the artwork is not always possible.
  - Engraving of Portrait of Thomas H. Fenton, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Oil Painting on Board, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook 1 by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook 2 by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbook 3 by Unidentified Artist, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook 4 by Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook 5 by Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sketchbook 6 by Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - Sketchbook 7 by Emily Clayton Bishop, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Sketchbook 8 by Emily Clayton Bishop, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Sketches, Loose, 1903-1943, undated (Box 7, Folder 14-19)
  - Sketches, Watercolors, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Two Oversized Sketches by Unidentified Artists, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook, 1905-1925; Series 8; 1 Folders Box 10
  This series consists of one scrapbook containing clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs concerning Marjorie Martinet.
  - Scrapbook, 1905-1925, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Printed Material, 1865-1984; Series 9; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 7-8, 10
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Fenton and others, programs, brochures, reproductions of artwork, picture postcards from various trips, a published thesis by Beatrice Fenton's sister Doris, yearbooks from Oldfields School, and miscellaneous printed material including a blueprint for the Memorial to Mrs. Eli Kirk Price.
  - Book, A Study in Karma by Anne Besant, 1918 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Books, Life Ahead and The Flight of the Eagle by J. Krishnamurti, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Book, The Influence of the Zodiac Upon Human Life by Eleanor Kirk, 1894 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Brochures for Art Supplies, 1928-1931, undated (Box 7, Folder 24-26)
  - Brochures for Beatrice Fenton, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Brochures for Martinet School of Art, 1915-1943, undated (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Brochures for Miscellaneous Art Schools, 1911-1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
  - Brochures for Oldfields School, 1960, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Brochures, Miscellaneous, 1923-1973 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Brochures, Travel, 1951-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 36-39)
  - Clippings, 1901-1926 (Box 7, Folder 40-76)
  - Clippings, 1927-1940 (Box 8, Folder 1-25)
  - Clippings, 1943-1949 (Box 8, Folder 26-33)
  - Clippings, 1952-1957 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, 1973-1984 (Box 8, Folder 36-37)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Beatrice Fenton, 1910-1946, undated (Box 8, Folder 38-42)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1908-1978, undated (Box 8, Folder 43-44)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1907-1947, undated (Box 8, Folder 45-47)
  - Picture Postcards of California, undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Picture Postcards of Eastern United States, undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Picture Postcards of France and Italy, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Picture Postcards of Grand Canyon, undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Picture Postcards of Oregon, Washington, and Canada, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Picture Postcards of Philadelphia, undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Picture Postcards of Utah and Wyoming, undated (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Picture Postcards of Yellowstone Park, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Programs and Tickets, 1865-1944 (Box 8, Folder 56-57)
  - Prospectus for the National Academy of Design, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Beatrice Fenton, undated (Box 8, Folder 59-64)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Marjorie Martinet, undated (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Others, undated (Box 8, Folder 66-67)
  - Published Thesis, The Extra-Dramatic Moment in Elizabethan Plays Before 1616 by Doris Fenton, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Yearbook, Oldfields School, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Yearbook, Oldfields School, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Oversized Poster and Reproduction of Artwork, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    One poster for the Martinet School of Art and one printed reproduction of artwork by Puvis de Chavannes.
- Photographs, 1890-1978; Series 10; 1 Linear feet Boxes 9-10, MGP 6
  Photographs are of Beatrice Fenton, her family, colleagues, models, her studio, art classes, artwork by Fenton and others, and miscellaneous exhibitions and installations. There are also albums containing photographs of friends and trips to Europe.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  10.1: Photographs of People, 1890-1978
  10.2: Photographs of Classes and Studios, 1909-1978
  10.3: Photographs of Artwork, 1912-1915
  10.4: Photograph Albums, 1909-1910
  - People, 1890-1978; 10.1
    - Beatrice Fenton, 1891-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1-10)
      See also Box 10. Two glass plate negatives housed in MGP 6.
    - Lizzie Remak Fenton, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Thomas H. Fenton, 1890-1929 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Family Members, undated (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
    - Emily Clayton Bishop, undated (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - Marjorie Martinet, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Friends, undated (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
    - Friends in Costume for the Play The Daughters of Troy, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 21-22)
    - Friends in Various Costumes, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Models (Wrestlers), undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Oversized Photographs of Beatrice Fenton and Thomas H. Fenton, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 2 Glass negatives (Box MGP 6)
  - Classes and Studios, 1909-1978; 10.2
    - Studio, 1978, undated (Box 9, Folder 25-27)
    - Art Classes, 1909 (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
    - Art Classes at Oldfields School, undated (Box 9, Folder 30-32)
    - Miscellaneous Art Classes Taught by Marjorie Martinet, undated (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
  - Artwork, 1912-1915; 10.3
    This subseries includes one folder of photographs of exhibitions and installations.
    - Artwork by Beatrice Fenton, undated (Box 9, Folder 35-56)
    - Artwork by Emily Clayton Bishop, 1912-1915, undated (Box 9, Folder 57-59)
    - Artwork by Marjorie Martinet, undated (Box 9, Folder 60-61)
      One glass plate negative housed in MGP 6.
    - Artwork by Unidentified Sculptors, undated (Box 9, Folder 62-67)
    - Miscellaneous Exhibitions and Installations, undated (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Oversized Photographs of Artwork, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)